Romanov Aleksey | Frontend Developer

Portfolio: name-romanov.com Location: Prague, Czech Republic

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/procellis33 Phone: +420 608 190 285

GitHub: github.com/procellis33 Email: aleksey55121@gmail.com

Professional Profile

I am an experienced developer seeking mainly **full-time position** with **long-term cooperation**. I possess a **maturita**, which grants me **free access to the Czech labour market**. I am proficient in working with **Czech-speaking** or **English-speaking** teams.

My main specialization is frontend development, but I also have experience with backend. I help clients to bring their ideas to life by working on web, mobile, or desktop applications. My experience allows me to create applications from scratch or improve existing projects.

For a more in-depth look at skills and projects, please visit my Personal Portfolio Website or GitHub.

Core Skills

- Typescript
- React
- Tailwind
- shaden/ui

- Next.js
- Vite
- TanStack
- Zod

- HTML
- Biome
- Framer Motion

Other Skills

Solid, JavaScript, React Native, Electron, Redux / RTK / Redux Saga, CSS / SCSS, Styled Components, Bootstrap, REST / GraphQL, Webpack, Zustand, ESLint, Prettier, Figma, Jest / Cypress, Git / GitLab, Convex, Clerk, Liveblocks, Redis, PostgreSQL, PL/pgSQL, OracleDB, PL/SQL, Golang, Docker, CI/CD, SonarQube, OpenStack, OpenShift, Trello and more.

Career Summary

Freelance — Frontend Developer

Mar 2024 - Present

I have worked on many frontend projects. I've successfully helped clients to create several web/Electron projects from scratch using React and Solid. I also worked on existing projects, ranging from simple landing pages to relatively large applications, where I developed key logic. My tasks varied from improving the UI/UX of pages to writing custom utility libraries.

ЕрмакДом — Fullstack Developer

May 2023 - Mar 2024

The "ErmakDom" application was created with the goal of digitizing the operations of a construction company. In the application, employees have specific roles and functions such as Project Manager, Technical Supervisor, Finance, or Supply. This application allows the company to store the history of past and current construction projects, control the construction process, view progress, manage employees, and more.

Initially, I thought through the entire application logic based on the client's requirements. Then, I designed the application architecture and developed frontend and backend from scratch. On the frontend, I used React Native and TypeScript. On the backend, I used Go, PostgreSQL, and Redis.

Professional development

Sep 2022 - May 2023

I took a break for studies at CTU FIT, where I learned fundamentals such as C, C++, Assembler, computer logic, advanced data structures, efficient data handling and the architecture of computers. Later, I delved into DevOps and different databases.

Verdeco — Frontend Developer

Apr 2021 - Oct 2022

Initially, I accumulated experience within the team by completing simple tasks such as adding new components and fixing bugs. Subsequently, I progressed as a frontend developer to handling more challenging assignments, including the creation of crucial components with key logic, refactoring legacy code, optimizing the application, engaging in code reviews, and occasionally participating in technical interviews.

The project had a primary focus on logistics, accounting, and finance.

Projects

Collaborative Whiteboard

Collaborative Whiteboard is built with React, Next.js, and TypeScript. There users can create organizations, invite members to them, create whiteboards, and collaborate in real time with other members.

GitHub link: github.com/procellis33/collaboration-whiteboard

Project showcase: https://youtu.be/43_2mJxDjWY

Calendar App

Calendar app is built with React, Vite, and TypeScript. It's a tool for managing schedules and events. Reminders, notifications, and the ability to share plans with others. Compatible with Google Calendar.

Project showcase: https://youtu.be/8XOdtP_wgYQ

Education

- > Faculty of Information Technology CTU, Prague Bachelor degree (Sep 2022 Present)
- ➤ 1. Slavic Gymnasium, Prague Maturita (Sep 2018 Jun 2022)